Some products, product categories and products from brands enrolled in Amazon
brand registry require approval before you can list them.
Applications help
customers shop with confidence knowing products are safe and authentic.
The
application will occur during the listing process and will look slightly
different depending on if you're selling a product that already exists in the
Amazon store or if you're selling a product that is new to Amazon.
To start
navigate to the add a product page in Seller Central.
In the search tab search
for your product.
If your product is already being sold in the Amazon store
click on your product from the search options.
If approval is required to sell
that product you'll see a message like you need approval to list this brand or
you need approval to list these products.
Select your product condition from the
drop-down menu then click apply to sell.
To list a new product first search to
confirm there's no existing listing.
If it doesn't appear in search results
click create a new listing.
You'll discover if your product requires category
approval when you select a product type.
Look for the learn more button with a
lock icon.
Click this button to open the help page categories and products that
require approval.
Find and click request approval next to the relevant
category.
You'll discover if you need brand approval while entering the brand
name.
Use the button in the message to access the selling application page.
You'll
have to submit a new application for each unique category or brand you want to
sell.
However once you have approval you will not have to resubmit an
application when listing other products in that same category or brand.
For
category approval the process is the same for both new and existing products.
You'll need to submit at least one purchase invoice from a manufacturer or
distributor.
Your invoice must meet these requirements dated within 180 days.
Includes your name and address matching your selling account.
Includes the
manufacturer or distributor's name and address and shows a combined purchase of
at least 400 units.
Check each box to confirm your document meets the
requirements.
You can omit pricing information if needed.
Upload your
invoice as a PDF, doc, PNG, GIF or JPEG file, maximum 10 MB.
Make sure it's
high resolution and in the correct orientation.
Provide your contact email
and optional phone numbers so we can reach you with questions.
Finally, click
submit.
When applying to sell a brand the process is different for new and
existing products.
For existing products select the document type you want to
upload either a purchase invoice from a manufacturer or distributor or an
authorization letter from the brand.
Purchase invoices must meet the same
requirements as category approvals.
Authorization letters must be dated within
180 days.
On the brand's letterhead include your name and address matching
your selling account and include the brand's name and address.
After uploading
your documents provide your contact information and any optional comments then
click submit.
Note that brand approval lets you match offers to existing product
detail pages.
It doesn't provide listing privileges to create or edit pages or
access to brand benefits like stores and a plus content.
Those are reserved for
sellers internal to the brand and authorized resellers.
For new products
you'll need to get an authorization letter from the brand directly.
You'll
provide the authorization letter from the brand plus product information and
images to create the new ASIN and product detail page.
This is the only
scenario where a seller other than the brand owner or authorized reseller can
apply to create a new listing for a brand enrolled in Amazon brand registry.
After submitting your application you'll receive confirmation within 24 hours
that we're reviewing your request.
Most reviews are completed within three
business days.
To check your application status go to view selling applications
in Seller Central.
Once approved click list products to start adding products to
your inventory.